A Guide to the Harrisonburg Historic Map Collection, 1873-1982 (bulk 1903-1956): SC 0050
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
Harrisonburg Historic Map Collection,
1873-1982,
(bulk 1903-1956)
Special Collections, James Madison University
Harrisonburg (Va.). Department of Planning and Community Development
SC 0050
5.19 cubic feet; 6 boxes, 6 map folders
The Harrisonburg Historic Map Collection, 1873-1982 (bulk 1903-1956), consists of approximately 615 items including maps, blueprints, drawings, and corresponding paperwork created by the City of Harrisonburg. These items represent proposed road improvements, sewer and water lines, bridge plans, land exchanges, and sub-divisions added to the city. Some drawings for church buildings, schools, parks and industrial zones are included as well.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
This collection is made up of two separate donations. Previously cataloged as MAP 9000, the original collection was donated to JMU Special Collections in January 2012 with an additional acquisition in August 2015. The 2012 portion of the collection was donated by Susan Versen of Massanutten Regional Library, who received the materials from Sam Hottinger at the Department of Planning and Community Development for the City of Harrisonburg, Virginia. The 2015 portion of the collection was donated by Kathy Walker, a GIS Technician of Community Development in Harrisonburg, Virginia.
Provenance
This collection of maps and corresponding paperwork was funded by the City of Harrisonburg. The items in this collection are duplicates of items found in the Department of Community and Development for the City of Harrisonburg, Virginia. After pulling the duplicate items, the department gave the maps to the Massanutten Regional Library who in turn donated them to Special Collections.
Biographical / Historical
The City of Harrisonburg was founded in 1779 as the result of a small land deed from Thomas Harrison, establishing Court Square. In 1849, Isaac Hardesty was elected Harrisonburg's first mayor. The City was incorporated as an independent city in 1916. Since its founding in 1779, the City of Harrisonburg has grown from two and a half acres of land to 11,132.16 acres (11.64 square miles). The Harrisonburg Historic Map Collection was created and compiled by the Harrisonburg Department of Planning and Community Development. The department oversees development and planning within the City of Harrisonburg. Among other things, the department maintains a Comprehensive Plan and zoning ordinance. The department is divided into three divisions:
- Building Inspections
- Engineering
- Planning and Zoning
The Building Inspections division oversees code interpretation, permits, and provides assistance to ensure new building projects are planned in compliance with City and building codes.
The Engineering division provides engineering and surveying, public works inspections, and geographic information systems (GIS).
The Planning and Zoning division promotes development according to the City's Comprehensive Plan and government laws by making recommendations to elected and appointed city officials about proposed development based on facts and public forums. This division also supports the department by checking for zoning violations and planning for city zoning or rezoning.
Scope and Content
The Harrisonburg Historic Map Collection, 1873-1982 (bulk 1903-1956), consists of approximately 615 items. The collection mostly consists of blueprints created by the city regarding street expansions, sewer lines and treatment plans, plans for bridge construction, street grades, sub-division additions to the city, and property exchanges. Half of the property exchanges are between private citizens and the City of Harrisonburg while the other half of the property exchanges are between private citizens only. These items are duplicates of maps found at the Department of Planning and Community Development for the City of Harrisonburg, Virginia.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series, chronologically, then alphabetically, within each series. All items in the collection are described at an item level.
Series 1: Paperwork, 1873-1967 (bulk 1910-1955) Series 2: Maps, 1903-1982 (bulk 1903-1956)
When no date could be determined for the document, it was labeled as "Undated" and placed at the end of the chronology. All undated items are arranged alphabetically.
Related Material
Robert James Sullivan Jr. Papers, ca.1930-2013, SC 0003, Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University, Harrisonburg, VA.
Location of Originals
The items in this collection are duplicates of items found at the Department of Community and Development for the City of Harrisonburg, Virginia.
Separated Material
The "Engineers' Manual, 1917" was removed from the map collection, cataloged, and placed within the Special Collections rare book collection.
Bibliography
City of Harrisonburg. "City of Harrisonburg History." harrisonburgva.gov. https://www.harrisonburgva.gov/history. Last Updated January 16, 2018. Accessed February 21, 2018.
City of Harrisonburg. "Community Development." harrisonburgva.gov. https://www.harrisonburgva.gov/community-development. Last Updated April 8, 2016. Accessed February 21, 2018.
City of Harrisonburg. "Building Inspections." harrisonburgva.gov. https://www.harrisonburgva.gov/building-inspections. Last Updated January 18, 2017. Accessed February 21, 2018.
City of Harrisonburg. "Engineering." harrisonburgva.gov. https://www.harrisonburgva.gov/engineering. Last Updated January 18, 2017. Accessed February 21, 2018.
City of Harrisonburg. "Planning & Zoning." harrisonburgva.gov. https://www.harrisonburgva.gov/planning-zoning. Last Updated January 18, 2017. Accessed February 21, 2018.
Index Terms
Subjects:
City planning -- Virginia -- Harrisonburg; Harrisonburg (Va.) -- History
Genre and Form Terms:
Letters (correspondence); Maps (documents); Blueprints (reprographic copies); Deeds; Plats (maps); Minutes (administrative records); Administrative records; Charters; profiles (orthographic projections); Drawings
- Series 1: Paperwork, 1873-1967 1910-1955
  Contents
  Series 1: Paperwork, 1873-1967 (bulk 1910-1955), consists of a single Hollinger box containing documents. Materials in this series include: sewer connection proposals, deed book references, contract templates, descriptions for land, and meeting minutes. Series 1 is arranged chronologically.
  - Agreement Between Harrisonburg and Valley Rail Road Copied from Council Minute Book "C" Page 16 & 17, 1873 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Extract taken from minutes of a special meeting held Feb. 16, 1910, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - J.A. Burkholder (Sewer Connection), 1911 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - J.H. McLaughlin (Sewer Connection), 1911 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Summary (Sewer Line), 1911 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - (Handwritten Contract) Z. Rexroades DB 93-344, Chas. L. Rhodes DB 93-P345 and J.H. McLaughlin DB93-P347, 1911 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Deed book 158 p. 135 Cavanaugh and Wyant/Conrad, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Deed Book 181 p. 256 Cavanaugh and Hayden, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Harrisonburg Mutal Telephone Company, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Portland Cement from D.L. Chaney to W.G. Myers (Coal Trestles), 1943 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Approval of Said Sub-Division By the Council of City of Harrisonburg, Virginia, and by the City Engineer, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Description of Old Municipal Building Property, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Employee Vacation Schedule American Finance Corp., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Description of Logan Land for Extension of South Ave. (document for Plat of South Ave thru Hugh A Logan), 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Dold L. Lineweaver to Mr. Earl Smith, Supt., Water & Sewer Dept., 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Metes and Bounds Description at the Shover Farm (documentation for Plat of Shover Farm), 1956 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Description of Annie Burke Good Est. Lot to be acquired by the City of Harrisonburg, Virginia, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - A.T. Massey Coal Co. 40' Street Proposal by Mr. T.R. Lokey (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Bill of Lumber (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Combination of Safe to Filing Cabinet (Instructions) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Contract Template (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Cooley Tract (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Description of Tract to be Conveyed to the City of Harrisonburg (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - List Showing No. of feet on each person, Persons with no sewer on their property (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Original Section Fill (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - The Charter of the City of Harrisonburg (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Timetable of Working Hours and Pay (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Series 2: Maps, 1903-1982 1903-1956
  Series 2: Maps, 1903-1982 (bulk 1903-1956) consists of large-sized maps contained within six folders in the Special Collections map drawers, small-sized maps contained within ten folders in two oversized flat boxes, laminated maps contained within two folders in one oversized flat box, and oversized maps that were too large to be to be adequately stored within the map case. Series 2 is arranged chronologically.
  - Plat showing a portion of Newman Avenue, 1903 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Cover and Dingledine Addition to Harrisonburg (Patterson Street), 1904 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plan for widening S. German Street, 1904 (Storage 1, Box 1)
  - Plan for Widening S. German Street South of Bruce St. Harrisonburg VA, part 1 (four parts), 1904 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plan for Widening S. German Street South of Bruce St. Harrisonburg VA, part 2, 1904 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plan for Widening S. German Street South of Bruce St. Harrisonburg VA, part 3, 1904 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plan for Widening S. German Street South of Bruce St. Harrisonburg VA, part 4, 1904 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plat of Public Square Harrisonburg Virginia showing adjacent streets and lots as now located (German St to Main St. and Court Square), 1904 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Heneberger and Grattan's Addition to the town of Harrisonburg Virginia (Campbell Street), 1905 (Box 3, Folder 5, Folder 1)
  - Plat of Lots in the town of Harrisonburg VA belonging to G.G. Grattan (Grattan Street), 1906 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plat of the North West Section town of Harrisonburg VA., 1906 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plat Showing Lots on Collicello Street in Harrisonburg, VA Belonging to Leon Wise, 1906 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plat Showing Proposed Site for the Location of Passenger Station Harrisonburg, VA. (W.Water St., German St., W.Market St.), 1906 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plat of Albert Ney's Lots on Paul Street Harrisonburg, VA, 1907 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plat of lots belonging to J.R. Lupton situated in the northern part of Harrisonburg, VA (between Collicello Street and North German Street), 1907 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of Depot Park Harrisonburg, VA (German Street, W. Water Street, W. Market Street), 1908 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map Showing Sub-division of A.G. Waterman's Farm Harrisonburg VA (between Rawley Springs Turn Pike and Mt. Clinton Pike), 1908 (Box 3, Folder 5, Folder 1)
  - Plan of Subdivision of Part of the Henry Ott est. Harrisonburg, VA as laid out by present owner A.M. Newman (Bruce Street., Newman Avenue) copy 1, 1908 (Box 3, Folder 5, Folder 1)
  - Plan of Subdivision of Part of the Henry Ott est. Harrisonburg, VA as laid out by present owner A.M. Newman (Bruce Street., Newman Avenue) copy 2, 1908 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of Lots Belonging to Albert and Alfred-Ney (Johnson Street, N. Main Street), 1909 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Map of Lots Belonging to C.C. Conrad (Paul Street, Mason Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of lots belonging to C.L. Rogers (Gay Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of lots belonging to H.C. Moore (Mason Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of Lots Belonging to J.C. Staples (Mason Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of lots Belonging to J.C. Staples and Co. (Mason Street, Grattan Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of lots owned by A.G. Waterman situated in Harrisonburg VA (Between Rawley Springs Turnpike and Mt. Clinton Turnpike), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of Ott Street Addition to Harrisonburg VA, 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of Park Place situated in Harrisonburg VA (Chicago Avenue, Green Street, High Street, Gay Street) copy 1 & 2, 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of property belonging to F.L. Sublett situated in Harrisonburg VA (German Street, Wolfe Street, Elizabeth Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of Property Belonging to the Harrisonburg Realty Co. (South Main Street), 1909 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Map of T.N. Thompson's Addition to Harrisonburg VA (Ott Street, Bruce Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map of the Liggett Lot situated in Harrisonburg VA (Bruce Street, and High Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Map Showing Proposed Extension of Academy Street, 1909 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plat of a small piece of land conveyed by the Town of Harrisonburg to J.N. Garber in exchange for another piece of land used in opening Mason Street (East Market Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plat of Carrington Lot as Subdivided by Roller and Martz (Rockingham Pike), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plat of Hill Top Farm situated at Harrisonburg VA Belonging to the Heirs of R.A. Gray Dec'd. As divided by G.R. Eastham, A.P. Eiler and J.G. Myers at the request of said heirs, 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plat of lot belonging to J.N. Garber (Mason Street, E. Market Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plat of the Carrington Lot as Subdivided by Roller and Martz (Rockingham Pike), 1909 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plat of the Strayer lot (W Market Street), 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Plat showing encroachments on the Mt. Clinton Pike, 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Property on Newman Ave., 1909 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - D.C Jones Addition to Harrisonburg Virgina as laid out June 17th 1873 (Wall St., Mason St, Wolfe St, Federal Street), 1910 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Garber and Garber Eastern Addition to Harrisonburg VA As laid out by J. Hawse March 1905, 1910 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of Ashby Park situated at Harrisonburg VA (between N Main Street, Washington Street, Ashby Avenue and Southern Railway, 1910 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of Land owned by The Town of Harrisonburg VA situated at the Hydro Electric Plant copy 1 & 2, 1910 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of Property Belonging to Mrs. K.S. Paul situated in Harrisonburg, VA, 1910 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of Proposed Siding Along the Property of the Snell Gro. And H'D'W. Co. Showing proposed exchange of land, 1910 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of Proposed Sub-Division of Land Belonging to Dr. R.S. Switzer Harrisonburg VA (Willow Street, Brook Avenue, between W. Market Street and Green Street), 1910 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of the Heneberger and Grattan Addition to Harrisonburg VA as laid out by J. Hawse March 1905 (Mason Street, Campbell Street), 1910 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plat of land owned by Dr. Frank Harris (W Elizabeth Street), 1910 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plat of Lot conveyed by JNO.P Burke to Dr. Amiss (Elizabeth Street, South High Street), 1910 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plat of Lot owned by Grover C. Curry (Reservoir Street), 1910 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plat of Lot Owned by Snell Gro. And H.D.W Co. (Water Street), 1910 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plat of Lots Belonging to Mrs. E. Purcell (Federal Street, Wolfe Street), 1910 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plat of Lots Belonging to Schuyler Bradely and Others (South High Street), 1910 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plat of the Caroline Crawford Lot Situated in Harrisonburg VA (Wolfe Street, Mason Street), 1910 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plat Showing Proposed Plan for Widening S.Main Street Along the Stephenson Property, 1910 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Profile of W. Bruce St., 1910 (Storage 1, Box 1)
  - Plat of land donated by A.G. Waterman to the town of Harrisonburg VA, for the purpose of establishing a public school (Mt. Clinton Pike) copy 1 & 2, 1911 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Department of the Interior U.S. Geological Survey Virginia-West Virginia, Woodstock Sheet Edition of April 1892, reprinted 1912, 1912 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plat of Lots in Harrisonburg belonging to the Estate of Jas. E. Rolle (S.Mason St), 1912 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - West Rock Street Grade, 1912 (Box 3, Folder 5, Folder 1)
  - Detail Drawing of Reinforced Concrete Reservoir Capacity 5,000,000 gallons, 1913 (Box 3, Folder 5, Folder 1)
  - Harrisonburg Virginia Plat Showing Strip of Land Required to Widen Gay St. said ground to come off of lot now owned by I.C. Oates, 1913 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Map of Proposed Sub-division of land belonging to Dr. R.S. Switzer, Harrisonburg, VA, 1913 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plan for Improvements at the Waterman School Harrisonburg VA., 1913 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plan for Improvements in the Depot Grounds Harrisonburg VA (Water Street, German Street, Market Street), 1913 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plan for Improvements in the Depot Grounds Harrisonburg VA. (Water St, German St, Market St), 1913 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plan of Side-walk on Main Street, 1913 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plat of property belonging to the Heirs of Dr. James Harris decd. Harrisonburg, VA (Cantrell Avenue), 1913 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plat showing strip of land required to widen Gay Street said ground to come off of lot now owned by I.C. Oates, 1913 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - West Market Street Bridge End- elevation North End, 1913 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - West Market Street Bridge Section-Showing Slab-re-enforcement, 1913 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of Subdivision of Land Belonging to Dr. R.S. Switzer Harrisonburg VA., 1913 (Box 3, Folder 5, Folder 1)
  - Map Showing the Alignment of East Elizabeth Street Harrisonburg VA., 1914 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Paul Street Grade Adopted by council Aug 11, 1914 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - Plat of "Brookland" Addition to the Town of Harrisonburg VA (W. Market Street, Elm Street, Willow Street, W. Water Street, Bruce Street, Brook Avenue), 1914 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plat of the "Masters & Brown" "Red Hill" Addition to Harrisonburg (Hawkins Street, E. View Street), 1914 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plat of the "Masters & Brown" "Red Hill" Addition to Harrisonburg (Reservoir Street, Hawkins Street, East View Street), 1914 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Plat showing location and boundary of the Old M.E. church lot Harrisonburg, VA (German Street, Graham Street, W Market Street), 1914 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Town of Harrisonburg Additional Land Required at the New Reservoir, 1914 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - German Street Bridge End-elevation, 1915 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - German Street Bridge Plan and Section Showing Re-Enforcement, 1915 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Main Street and E. Market Street Building line of Pilasters as allowed by council, 1915 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Main Street and E. Market Street Peoples Bank Encroachment line copy 1 & 2, 1915 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of the Layman Place Recently Purchased by the Town of Harrisonburg, 1915 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Patterson Street Grade, 1915 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plan for Improving Main St. Along the Jno. T. Harris Property, 1915 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Proposed Location Sewage Disposal Plant Harrisonburg VA on the Beery Land, 1915 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Sedimentation Tank Imhoff Patent Sewage Disposal Plant Harrisonburg VA, 1915 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - Profile Plate A, c.1915 (Storage 1, Box 1)
  - City of Harrisonburg Proposed Sewer Extension North of Gay Street, copy 1 & 2, 1916 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - East Water Street Extended Grade Profile, 1916 (Conatiner 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - Sewer on Main Street, Gay to Effinger, 1916 (Box OV 1, Folder 1)
  - Town of Harrisonburg Main Sewer Line Through the Land of M. Alice Berry and Children copy 1 & 2, 1916 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - Town of Harrisonburg Main Sewer Line Through the Land of W.W. Acker, 1916 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - General Location Sewage Disposal Plant Harrisonburg Virginia, 1917 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - Intermittent Sand Filters Sewage Disposal Plant Harrisonburg, VA, 1917 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - Map showing the alignment of E. Market Street east of Sterling Street copy 1 & 2, 1917 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - Retention or Dosing tank, sewage disposal plant Harrisonburg, VA, 1917 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - Water system Flume-pool diagram, 1917 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - Map of the Bradley Foundry Property (S. High Street, Fairgrounds), 1918 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Map showing land bought by C.C. Conrad from the Estate of R.S. Switzer Dec'd, 1918 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of Garber and Garber Additon City of Harrisonburg, 1919 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - Map of Lots Owned by the Rockingham Motor Co. Inc Harrisonburg, VA copy 1 & 2, 1919 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Map of proposed subdivision of land owned by C.C. Conrad Harrisonburg VA, 1919 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plan of Proposed Bridge Over Blacks Run on Bruce Street Harrisonburg-Virginia, 1919 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Plat of Edge Lawn lots, 1919 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Proposed Sewer Extension Conrad Addition copy 1 & 2, 1919 (Box OV 1, Folder 2)
  - Lots Owned by W. H. Funkhouser (E.Market St, Broad Street), 1920 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Map of lots owned by C.H. Heltzel (Valley Pike), 1920 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of Lots owned by G.W. Shaver-G.W. and O.A. Dovel Harrisonburg, VA, 1920 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of Proposed Location Silk Mill, 1920 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of Proposed Plan for Widening Bruce Street between High and Liberty copy 1 & 2, 1920 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of the Bradley Lot (S.High Street, Blacks Run), 1920 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Map of the Leake Lot (Wolfe St, Brook Ave. ), 1920 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Pitometer map of Harrisonburg VA, 1920 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 2)
  - Map of Maple-Hurst Addition Lots owned by H.M. Newman (S. Main Street and Port Republic Road, 1921 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of the J.M. Snell Warehouse Property, 1921 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Alta-Vista Addition to Harrisonburg Owned by Heirs of A.M. Newman Dec'd., 1922 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of Lots Owned by W.E. Fry (Mason St, Cantrell Ave), 1922 (Box OV 3, Folder 1)
  - Map of Property Owned by E.B. Crawford Harrisonburg VA., 1922 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of Property Purchased by Newtown Giant Incubator Corp. from Executors J.H. McGlaughlin Estate. Harrisonburg, VA copy 1 & 2, 1922 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Proposed Streets on the Lands of JNO. P. Burke and C.C. Conrad (W.Market St, Brook Ave. Wolfe St, Willow St, Chicago Ave, Green St.), 1922 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of the Sibert Addition to Harrisonburg VA copy 1 & 2, 1922, 1927 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - Map of Lots Owned by W.E. Frye (C-W R.R.to Main Street), 1923 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - (Item 1) Detail of Present Resorvoir, 1923 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 2)
  - (Item 2) City of Harrisonburg VA. Re-inforced Concrete Resorvoir Capactiy 15 million Gallons Detail of Sub Grade, 1923 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 2)
  - Brooke Ave Grade North of W. Market, 1923 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)
  - City of Harrisonburg Re-inforced Concrete Reservoir Capacity 15 millon Gallons Detail at Low Corner, 1923 (Container 3, Container 5, Folder 1)
  - John Gray Paul to the City of Harrisonburg, 1923 (Box OV 1, Folder 3)